Lombard General Insurance Company
Limited Q4 and FI 2025 earnings
conference call from the senior
management we have with us today Mr.
Sanjiv Mantri MD and CEO of the company
Mr. Gopal Palchandran CFO Mr. Girish
Nyak chief technology and health
underwriting and claims Mr. Sep Kuradyia
chief corporate solutions international
bank assurance Mr. Anand Singhi chief
retail and government business Mr. Gorov
Aurora, Chief Reinsurance, Underwriting
and Claims for Property and Casualty.
Please note that any statements comments
are made in today's call that may look
like forward-looking statements are
based on information presently available
to the management and do not constitute
any indication of any future performance
as future involves risk and
uncertainties which could cause results
to differ materially from the current
views being expressed. As a reminder,
all participant lines will be in the
listenon only mode and there will be an
opportunity for you to ask questions
after the presentation concludes. Should
you need assistance during the
conference call, please signal an
operator by pressing star then zero on
your touch on phone. I now hand the
conference over to Mr. Sanjie Mantri, MD
and CEO ICIC Lumbard General Insurance
Limited. Thank you and over to you.
Good evening to each one of you. Thank
you for joining the earning conference
call at ICL Lumbar General Insurance
Company Limited for quarter 4 and
financial year
2025. Let me give you a brief overview
of the trends we observed in the economy
as well as the industry followed by an
overview of the business. Post this our
CFO Mr. Gopal Walachandran will share
the financial performance of the company
for the quarter and the year ended 31st
March 2025.
The the GDP growth for the quarter ended
December 2024 stood at 6.2% versus
5.6% for the quarter ended September
2024. As per the data released by Moxy,
high frequency indicators like eway
bills, toll collections, diesel
consumption and GST collections during
quarter 4 of financial year 2025 are all
indicating positive economic conditions.
Further, Mopsy has revised the fullear
GDP estimates to 6.5% on Feb 28, 2025
versus 6.4% published on Jan 7,
2025. Let me not dwell on certain
industry trends which can have an impact
on the general insurance industry at
large. As indicated during the last
quarter, the government expenditure
remained flat which impacted the
commercial line segment growth for the
current quarter. However, we have
started seeing an uptick in government
spending towards capital expenditure in
past few months. This may be a positive
for the commercial line of business. For
the auto industry, we had seen a growth
in rural market in Q3 of 2025.
Specifically for two wheeler segment at
12.7% and the tractor segment at 20.1%.
as reported by far. However, in quarter
4, 2025, we have seen a degrowth of 1.9%
for the two-heer segment and a degrowth
of 4.6% for the tractor segment. This
indicates a softer rural demand. The
private car segment grew by 1.1% and the
commercial vements vehicle segment had a
degrowth of 3.8% 8% for quarter 4
financial year
2025 as reported by far which had an
impact on motor insurance growth for
quarter 4 financial year 2025. However,
for the coming year, the auto industry
is expected to have mid singledigit
growth. We remain positive for the motor
insurance business with increasing
penetration in the old vehicle segments.
The health segment continues to be one
of the fastest growing segments and is
the largest contributor to the industry
constituting 38.1% of the GDP mix for
financial year 2025. However, the
industry growth in financial year 2025
was impacted due to the one by
accounting norm and lower growth in the
health segment health benefit segment
attributable to lower dispersement by of
credit by NBFCs and MFIs. We believe
that the increasing demand for health
protection coupled with increased
medical inflation may drive doubledigit
growth in the health segment in the
coming
year. There were some key economic
changes which were announced during
quarter 4 financial year
2025. The budgetary announcement of
income tax relief provided is expected
to result in an additional 1 trillion in
the hands of Indian tax population
thereby leading to a high disposable
income. The second consecutive interest
rate cut tweaking of norms applicable to
NBFC lending coupled with in inclusion
of liquidity by RBI should also support
credit
growth. These policy changes aim to
encourage spending and investment. They
are also expected to stimulate demand
for goods and services thereby boosting
consumption and preparing demand for
risk protection through insurance
solutions.
However, we remain vigilant on the
ongoing geopolitical developments which
may pose risk to both global growth and
the Indian economy. Now, let me give you
a brief give you an update on the
regulatory developments. The regulatory
the authority during financial year 2025
continued with various reforms seeking
to expand the market and increase the
penetration of insurance product towards
the mission of insurance for all by
2047.
I would like to mention key circulars
which were introduced in quarter 4 2025
regarding capping the increase in senior
citizens health insurance premium rates
to 10% peranom and introduction of Bimma
ESBA facility for health insurance
policies. We believe these regulatory
changes will improve affordability and
create operational ease for policy
holders.
Overall, we remain positive that the GI
industry is poised to grow in the medium
to long-term given the favorable
economic and regulatory environment, low
penetration and relatively higher
disposable
income. Now coming to the industry
performance for quarter 4 and financial
year
2025, the gross direct premium income
grew by 1.7% and 6.2% for quarter 4 2025
and financial year 2025 respectively.
Excluding the impact of the one by
accounting norm, the GDPI grew by 8.6%
for financial year
2025. Excluding crop and math health,
the GDPI grew by 4.9% and 8% for quarter
4 2025 and financial year 2025
respectively. Speaking on the specific
segments within the industry, the
commercial segment reported a marginal
degrowth of 1.2% 2% and growth of 1.5%
for quarter 4 and financial year 2025.
Within this, the fire segment registered
a degrowth of 1.8% and 5.3% for quarter
4 financial year 2025 and financial year
2025 respectively on account of pricing
pressure excluding the fire segment. The
over overall commercial segment grew by
8 and a half% for financial year 2025.
The motor segment grew by 6.9% for
quarter 4 of financial year 2025 and 8%
for financial year 2025. The growth in
the segment has been lower due to muted
vehicle sales and continued pricing
pressures reflected by high industry
combined
ratio. The health the health segment
grew at 3.7% and 9% for quarter 4 2025
and financial year 2025. Within this
group health grew at 4.5% and 10.6% for
quarter 4 2025 and financial year 2025
respectively and retail health grew at
7.6% and 12.1% in quarter 4 2025 and
financial year 2025 respectively.
Looking at the underlying performance of
the industry, you may recall our
discussion a year back during a earnings
call where we expect we where we
expected some semblance in underwriting
discipline in the market due to
improvement in the industry's combined
ratio during that period. However, the
combined ratio for the industry has
actually worsened to
113.2% for 9 month as against 112.2% 2%
for 9 months financial year 2024. The
combined ratio for the private sector
has worsened to triple 1.21% for 9 month
2025 from 108.3% for 9 month financial
year 2024. The industry worsening was
largely due to motor segment combined
ratio which increased to 123.8% in 9
month financial year 2025 as against
118.2% in 9 month financial year 2024.
Our continued focus on driving
profitable growth helped us to improve
our combined ratio from
103.7% in 9 month financial year 2024 to
102.8% in 9 months financial year 2025
and
103.3% in full financial year 2024 to
102.6% in financial for the financial
year 2025 on NBC
basis. I will now walk you through the
company performance across key business
segments during quarter 4 and financial
year 2025.
The company's GDPR registered a growth
of 8% for quarter 4 2025 and 11% for
financial year 2025 on NBC basis. With
the 1 byN accounting norm for quarter 4
2025, the company registered a growth of
2.3% is as against the industry growth
of
1.7%. And for financial year 2025, the
company registered a growth of 8.3% as
against the industry growth of 6.2%.
Excluding crop and mass health, the
company's growth was 2.2% and
7.7% compared to the industry growth of
4.9% and 8% for quarter 4 2025 and
financial year 2025
respectively. In the commercial line
segment in quarter 4 2025, our growth
was at 2.8% as against the industry the
growth of 1.2%. For financial year 2025,
we grew by 2.5
2.1% as against the industry growth of 1
and a half% thereby maintaining market
share. This indicates the strength of a
brand relationship and service quality
in an environment where industry faced
continued pricing pressure throughout
the year. In the fire segment, we grew
in line with the industry and in marine
cargo engineering and liability lines of
business, we reported growth higher than
the industry leading to market share
accretion.
In motor segment we grew at.1% per
quarter for 2025 as against the industry
growth of
6.9%. We continue to drive our motor
strategy based on granular portfolio
segmentation and prudent risk selection.
For the financial year 2025 we grew by
11 and a half% as against the industry
growth of 8%. Consequently our market
share grew to 10.8% 8% for financial
year 2025 versus 10.5% for financial
year 2024. The portfolio mix for private
car, two wheeler and CV stood at 53.4%,
25.4% and 21.2% respectively. Our
continued focus on multi- channelannel
distribution, underwriting capabilities
and efficient claim settlement and
actual practices helped us in
maintaining our leadership position.
Moving to the health segment, we grew by
22.1% and 19.2% for quarter 4 financial
year 2025 and financial year 2025
respectively with the one by accounting
now EQ by 9.7% and 12.6% for quarter 4
2025 and financial year 2025
respectively. Our retail health segment
registered a growth at 47.7% for quarter
4 financial year 2025 with the 1 byN
accounting norm. The growth of quarter 4
2025 was 25.1% as against the industry
growth of
7.6%. For financial year 2025 the
overall growth stood at
38.1%. With one by an accounting norm
the growth for financial year 2025 was
25%. As again the industry growth of
12.1%. As a result, we gained market
share from 3% in financial year 2024 to
3.3% for financial year
2025. The group health employed employee
segment witnessed growth of 24.9% and
18.5% for quarter 4 2025 and financial
year
2025 respectively. A group other
business debut by 5.5% and with the one
by an accounting norm that the growth
was 30% for quarter 4
2025 for financial year 2025 group other
business had a muted growth of 5.3% on
account of impact on health benefit
business through the banker channel with
the 1 byN accounting norm this segment
showed a
deg spoken about various one team
initiatives in a earlier earnings call.
One of the initiatives we had spoken
about was the consolidation of customerf
facing digital effects like take care
helps app website and digital alliances
under one digital to deliver a superior
customer experience and to drive
efficiency. Some of the digital outcomes
achieved in financial year 2025 include
increasing unique customer visit by 2x
on our digital platform. 37% growth in
fresh transactions on our digital
platform. Downloads for our one-stop
solution one take your app surprise
surpassed 14.9
million. The business done through the
app stood at 9 927.7 million and 2653.2
2 million for quarter 4, financial year
2025 and financial year 2025
respectively. Consequently, our
customerf facing digital asset business
grew by
15.8% constituting 6.6% of our overall
GDP for financial year
2025. Now I would like to share with you
some initiatives taken by us for
improving the customer experience and
driving efficiencies for
claims on the motor side. A preferred
partner network service
74.1% of our nonoem claims in quarter 4
2025 up from 69.6% in quarter 4 2024.
For financial year 2025 this number
stood at
73.2% up from 65% in financial year
2024. Our cloud calling facilities were
used by 89.6% 6% of our motor customers
in quarter 4 financial year 2025 has
against 77% in quarter 4 2024. For the
full year this number was at 86% as
against 49% previous year. This resulted
in a reduction of cost to claim ratio by
21% for the
year.
Our average claim settlement period for
retail lines of business has seen
improvement from 6 days in financial
year 2024 to 5 days in financial year
2025 for motor and for motor and for
five and for 5 days in financial year
2024 to 3 days in financial year 2025
for health. Our is act initiative which
was launched in April 2024 offered an
onground claim support to over 90,000
customers across 56 cities and 2
hospital network in financial year
2025. A focus on customer experience and
process efficiencies has led to healthy
NPS of 67 and 69 for health and motor
claims respectively for 9 months
2025. With all the above efforts, we are
pleased to share that the company's
premium growth has been higher by 210
basis points. As again the industry
growth, our focus on driving profitable
opportunities has
f combined ratio from
103.3% in financial year 2024 to 102.6%
in financial year 2025 on
NBC's on on the 1 byN accounting norm.
The combined ratio stood at
102.8% leading to a pad growth of
30.7% and then delivering ROE for the
year at 19.1%.
As we enter into the new financial year,
we remain committed to achieving the
desired scale through creation of
positive customer experiences,
leveraging data analytics and a
technology first approach. Harnessing a
multi-roduct multi-distribution strategy
and with a continued focus on product
innovation with a core philosophy of one
team, we continue to scale up the profit
pools and to drive sustainable growth.
I will now request Gopar to take you
through the financial numbers for the
recently concluded quarter and financial
year. Thanks Sanjie and uh good evening
to each one of you. I will now give you
a brief overview of the financial
performance for the recently concluded
quarter and the financial year. We have
uploaded the results presentation on our
website. You can access it as we walk
you through the performance numbers.
With effect from October 1, 2024,
long-term products are accounted on a 1
byN basis as mandated by the regulator.
Hence, Q4 and FI25 numbers are not
comparable with prior periods. For more
details on the impact, refer to slide
number 15 of our investor presentation
for further details. The gross direct
income of the company was at rupes
268.33 billion in FI25 as against rupes
247.76 billion in FI24. a growth of 8.3%
as against industry growth of
6.2%. GDP of the company was at 62.11
billion in Q4 FI25 as against 60.73
billion in Q4 FI24. A growth of 2.3% as
against industry growth of
1.7%. On the retail side of the
business, GDP of the portal segment was
at 107.4 billion in FI25 as against
96.34 billion in FI24, registering a
growth of 11.5%.
The advanced premium for the motor
segment was at rupes 37.17 billion at
March 31 2025 as against 36.44 billion
as at December 31 2024. GDP of the
health segment was at rupes 69.5 billion
in FI25 as against 61.71 billion in FI24
registering a growth of 12.6%. Our agent
which includes the point of sale
distribution count was at 1 lak 40,736
as at March 31 2025 up from 1 lakh 40,77
as at December 31 2024. GDP of our
commercial line segment was at 69.95
billion in FI25 as against 68.51 billion
in FI24 registering a growth of 2.1% as
against industry growth of
1.5%. Resultedly our combined ratio
stood at 102.8% 8% for FI25 as against
103.3% for FI24 excluding the impact of
CAT losses of 94 billion in FI25 and
1.37 billion in FI24. The combined ratio
was 102.4% and 102.5% respectively.
Combined ratio for quarter 4 FI25 was
102.5% as against 102.3% in quarter 4
FI24. Our investment assets during the
quarter rose to rupes 535.0 08 billion
as at March 31 2025 up from rupes 515.99
97 billion as at December 31 2024 our
investment leverage net of borrowings
was 3.74 times as at March 31 2025 as
against 3.76 times at December 31 2024
investment income was at 42.5 billion in
FI25 as against 36.1 billion in FI24 on
a quarterly basis investment income was
at 8.77 billion in Q4 FI25 as against
9.54 billion in Q4
FI24. Our capital net of impairment on
investment assets stood at rupees 8.02
billion for the full year as compared to
5.51 billion in the previous financial
year. Capital gains net of impairment on
investment assets stood at
rupees.06 billion in quarter 4 FI25 as
compared to rupees 1.56 billion in
quarter 4 FI24. Our profit before tax
grew by 30% at 33.21 billion in FI25 as
against 25.55 billion in FI24. Whereas
PBT grew by 4.2% at 6.68 billion in
quarter 4 FI25 as against 6.98 billion
rupees in quarter 4 FI24. Consequently,
profit after tax grew by 30.7% at 25.08
08 billion in FI25 as against 19.19
billion in FI24. PAT degrrew by 1.9% to
rupees 5.1 billion in Q4 FI25 as against
5.19 billion in quarter 4 FI24. The
board of directors of the company has
proposed a final dividend of rupees 7
per share for FI25. This statement is
however subject to approval of
shareholders in the ensuing annual
general meeting of the company. The
overall dividend for FI25 including the
proposed final dividend is rupes 12.5
per share. Last year the overall
dividend was rupees 11 per share. Return
on average equity was 19.1% in FI25 as
against 17.2% in FI24. Return on equity
for quarter 4 this year was 14.5 as
against 17.8 in quarter 4 of last year.
Solveny ratio was at 2.69 69 times at
March 31, 2025 as against 2.36 times at
December 31, 2024 continued to be higher
than the regulatory minimum requirement
of 1.5. As I conclude, I would like to
assert that we remain focused on our
strategy of driving profitable growth,
consistent and sustainable value
creation for all our stakeholders while
ensuring that the interest of policy
holders is in the forefront at all
times. I'd like to thank you all for
attending this earnings call and we will
be happy to take any questions that you
may have. Thank you.
Thank you. We will now begin the
question and answer session. Anyone who
wishes to ask a question may press star
and one on the touchstone telephone. If
you wish to remove yourself from the
question queue, you may press star and
two. Participants are requested to use
handsets while asking a question. Ladies
and gentlemen will wait for a moment
while the question queue
assembles. The first question comes on
the line of P chain from Mutal OA
financial services limited. Please go
ahead. Yeah. Hi. Uh a good set of
numbers on especially on the combined
ratio front. uh just your thoughts on uh
you know how do we see the growth from
here? Uh firstly you know from a overall
BWP perspective uh given the one by
impact would continue uh to be there in
one match of next one of 26 and second
half would see unwinding of uh uh the
GWP uh and contributing to some part of
growth. So that would be uh the first
question. Uh second question would be on
your combined ratio whether you would
look at combined ratio further improving
from the one that reported uh in in the
for
FI25 and uh bit on the fire segment if
you could highlight you know what are
the kind of renewals we've seen in
January and also in in the uh in the
April renewals and those would be a
three question. Thanks.
Okay. Yeah. Thanks. I think uh with
respect to the growth uh even when I was
reading in terms of uh what it is line
by line I had covered but again I I'll
talk about it uh motor per se expecting
on the new cell
miss by other OEM as to what they are
seeing. Albeit the base on the private
car in particular is high. Uh I also
spoke about the fact that the quarter
four two wheeler numbers were there were
negative which was a bit of a surprise
as well as what we saw in quarter three
and commercial vehicle I would be more
positive overall because government
capex and lot of other activities which
in the last
financial should get picked up. So netn
net net motor we will see single digit
to maybe just about double digit growth
is what our prediction is and look all
of these things can change real time
we'll keep you updated but that's what
our belief is on the health side p our
own belief is we will should see double
digit growth uh now health is two
components retail health and as well as
the group health part of it I'm more
clearly talking about the retail health
part which will continue to see far more
uh incremental business in terms of new
to insurance and also there will be
whatever interest rate growth that comes
out in terms of overall this. So we will
remain positive on health and health
with a 38% contribution will not be
surprised if you see that contribution
probably going to a 40% and thereabouts
and becomes the largest and will
continue to be the largest player. Then
last but uh not the least in terms of
the commercial line of business uh we've
had a very one of the most difficult
years on commercial line if you see uh
we've never seen a growth of this nature
going to you know no single digit in
last 7 to 8
years clearly it had multiple factors
fire pricing which we spoke about it
however going forward as the and you
spoke about and I'll probably talk about
the other question that you put across
we saw a lot of semblance in the
industry overall on the fire
side and on that basis we do believe and
we do see relatively much better numbers
on fire and with the activity of the
capex which is coming through
engineering line of business should also
do well so overall commercial we would
like to believe that there should be a
it should be back to a double digit kind
of a growth at the industry level I
think your last question was on the
combine on the combine all right so I
think pre Again if you look at what we
have been saying is uh obviously our
performance will will be in the context
of how the market uh performs. So which
is why we kind of also put that as a
part of the opening uh transcript as in
to say that at the beginning of the
financial year concluded we had kind of
possibly expected a lot more semblance
to pay out but in reality if you look at
I think the market seems to have gone
slightly more in that sense north. I
think combined ratios have kind of
increased by almost about 100 basis
point at an aggregate level. So
obviously we'll wait for the full year
numbers to play out in terms of what the
players report but obviously we will be
at it when it comes to let's say driving
profitable opportunities. So hence the
endeavor will be obviously to try and
see how we can create lot more
efficiencies whether it is on loss
ratios cost etc etc and obviously select
the right portfolio mix but obviously we
will see how the market direction plays
out and in that context is how we would
also want to see our combined play
through but having said that definitely
I think the gap between us and the
industry combined whichever way you look
at it I think obviously we will be able
to kind of do lot more uh positives to
play out and in the aggregate I think
what we have spoken about is time and
again we will look for trying to see if
we can do that improvement in the return
on equity that we can give to
stakeholders uh the range that we have
generally spoken about in that range of
16 to 18% the endeavor will be to
obviously try and see over the long term
to move towards the 18 to 20 depending
on how the market plays out yeah so I
think and so the simple answer is uh
would we like to improve our combine uh
certainly yes uh and as Gopal mentioned
uh we saw a trajectory when we came in
last year where industry combine had
shown an improvement on the basis of
that we felt we will go uh we also would
like to see a similar thing but the
duration has happened and the deteration
more so has happened in terms of motor
moving from 118 to 123 for a 9 month
combined but so that being said we will
let uh these things play out uh and in
our mind the single factor that drives
is are we able to generate the roe and
that's what largely Gopal is speaking
about is it uh as far as we as a you
know uh as an entity is concerned.
Just your thoughts on motor to be
prioritized that will be my
last we always remain hopeful but uh no
news as yet. So uh is the industry
seeking it? Answer is yes. Is it come
through? The answer is
no in that sense. Yes. Yes. Okay. Yeah,
thank you so much.
Thanks.
Thank you. A reminder to all the
participants in the interest of time
please restrict questions to two per
participants. Next question comes from
the line of Aset Koda with Aendes Park.
Please go ahead.
Yeah, thank you for the opportunity
goal. In the current quarter we seems to
have done little more reinsurance
accepted business because there is a
meaningful difference between GDPI and
GWP in the quarter almost 10%age. So
just wanted to understand the color of
this business and um do you see uh
opportunity and reinsurance accepted
with price hike going up probably you
will do the same kind of a business in
in subsequent year also. uh any any
thoughts on those lines just just want
to understand and and the second
question uh goal was that uh uh you see
see if you if you could not book capital
gains in the current quarter uh your
yield remained at 6.3 suppose
hypothetically market remains weak
largely for fi26 so so is it fair to say
that your 6.3 6.4 4 is the yield for for
uh for for for probably for the entire
FI26 and therefore we need to look ro
from from from that perspective. Just
wanted to understand that a bit from you
and lastly data keeping question if you
can give retail health loss issue
breakup and motor GWP break up into new
and old which you usually do. Thank you.
Yeah, maybe I think I'll first uh do the
data keeping question first uh which is
something that keeps coming to us every
quarter. Uh so I'm just kind of giving
you the numbers both for Q4 of last year
and Q4 of this year first and then I
will give the numbers for the full year
in terms of the break up between
corporate health and uh the retail
indemnity numbers. Uh so quarter 4 of
last year corporate health uh loss
ratios were
88.1%. And the retail indemnity numbers
again for quarter 4 of last year was
64.6%.
Visually this quarter four of this year
corporate health is at
97.2%. And retail health broadly the
range that we have spoken about is at
about
64.8%. On a full year basis this number
for corporate health stands at about
93.7 last year and the current year re I
mean again last year retail indemnity
numbers is
65.4. Full year this number for
corporate health is at 97.6 6 and retail
indemnity is
67.9. So that's the numbers in terms of
the break up between corporate health
and retail health. Now coming to your
point first question on reinsurance
accepted uh one at an aggregate level
obviously if you ask us underwriting
philosophy is to drive profitable growth
whether it is with respect to the gross
direct premium income that we write or
even with respect to let's say the
reinsurances acceptances to the extent
whatever we do. So therefore from a
philosophy standpoint I think we will
stand committed to driving profitable
growth across the revenue streams that
we source. Having said that I think if
you look at at an aggregate level I
think in terms of the roughly the
premium that we would have written of
close to about 28,000 crores or
thereabout the extent of reinsurance in
world will be a singledigit number. Um
so hence to that extent I think a large
part of the opportunities is what we see
clearly even in the domestic market.
Plus at the same time obviously we look
for given the fact that we also have an
office in our IIO uh business we would
want to kind of continue to see how we
can leverage profitable opportunities
even through the IIO business. So hence
that is how we would kind of play
through whether a particular business
comes through in a quarter or otherwise
I think again as I keep saying our
business is significantly cyclical and
wherever we see opportunities play out
is how you will continue to see the mix
of business between direct ra etc etc
play out the larger number to look at
will be more on an annual basis that
will be more reflective of where we are
in terms of our approach to writing
domestic and reinsurance in
world second point on Uh yeah sorry go
ahead. So so this I was asking this
question predominantly because because
you you will see a better pricing
environment uh in next fiscal year. So
so if other segments slow down say motor
source downs a bit because of the weak
auto cycle. Uh is it fair to say that
this product might be an opportunity uh
approach to to uh to to drive the
overall growth maybe from that
perspective because environment.
Exactly. So your point is absolutely
right. That's exactly what I said. I
think if you ask us for us both of them
are preferred areas of opportunity. So
therefore to that extent where we see uh
preferable segments for us to be able to
underwrite we will look at both. Will it
suddenly become a very large proportion
of our overall revenue streams at this
point of time? Clearly not. But
obviously we will look at uh the as I
said profitable opportunities between
domestic and the reinsurance in the
revenues that we'll eventually source
will be mix of both.
uh on your point on capital gains, I
think uh if you look at u the uh
approach that we have taken in so far as
uh building the investment portfolio is
concerned, I think uh the treasury team
has done a brilliant job uh in terms of
how to kind of balance the mix of asset
classes between equity and the fixed
income portfolio and that's the reason
during this last periods of high
interest rate regime we have been able
to kind of significantly go long and
which is the reason I think even in our
earlier earnings call we have spoken
about of our duration of the book that
still continues to be slightly in excess
of uh 5.3 years and if you look at the
yield to maturity uh the yield to
maturity of the book also kind of
currently stands at about 7.55%.
And hence uh and this is what is kind of
translating into if you look at our
marktomarket positions on the overall
investment book while on the roughly an
aggregate mark tomarket gain as on the
balance sheet date of roughly about 1800
uh 18 billion um in terms of the mark to
market unrealized gains is what we have.
So I think the portfolio is well
positioned. The question to ask for is
what happens in case if you see possibly
sustained periods of price competition
or sustained periods of low interest
rate regime. Now all of that I think in
so in in so far as the second part of
let's say periods of low interest rate
sustaining in the next year I think to
that extent I think our duration call
will kind of largely reflect that and of
course incre reinvestment of the
incremental cash flows will get
subjected to getting placed at a lower
interest rate and that will be true for
the entire market. So therefore the
entire market will have to work much
more harder in terms of improving the
pricing and therefore on balance which
is what we keep saying I think the roe
range that we will work which will be
through a combination of driving
underwriting outcomes and return on
investment that will be in the range of
18 to 20%. assuming the market obviously
shows signs of change and also you know
sake now I'll just uh give you the you
know lay of the land uh if you go back
in time in April uh as we were finishing
our financial year
2024 if you would have told us to guess
the growth rate for commercial line of
business we would have said definitely
it will be in double digits uh if you
would have told us on the banker line of
business which is a big practice we have
again we would have said a decent with
double digits but as transpired in the
course of the year both of these lines
that are relatively difficult here but
again the emphasis that we have as a
multi-line multi- product companies are
we agile enough to toggle uh even you
look at the numbers that you see quarter
and quarter in motor we had a
significant gain in quarter 1 and
quarter two and again in quarter three
and quarter
four we have the PSUs which have built
up severe intensity which is not making
much of an economic sense
and you have seen us growing relatively
low while we finish the year overall
with a gain on market share. So what I'd
like to emphasize to all of you is uh
what we see and what comes through there
can be a gap and as an organization we
are expected to maintain that level of
agility to make those shifts happen and
what we predict not necessarily the way
the market will end up behaving. So we
we will have to factor that and again I
come back in light of that the focus
intently for us as an organization boils
down to are we able to generate the you
know uh that is expected by all our
stakeholders.
All right good. Yeah
please rejoin the queue for Mr. Gola.
Please rejoin the queue for more
questions. Thank you.
Next question comes on the line of
Nidesh Jen with Invest. Please go
ahead. Uh thanks. Thanks for the
opportunity. Two question. First is on
fire pricing. Are we already seeing
signs of improvement in fire pricing for
the industry?
Yeah, the answer is yes. There is uh uh
some semblance uh but I would like to
put a word of caution because uh we
still have to see a lot more flowing
through. But as things stand in uh first
couple of weeks of April there was uh
definitely much better discipline in the
market.
Yeah sure. Uh secondly can you speak
about IFRS impact on uh our
profitability or ROE any any rough
indication because some of the other
companies are are disclosing their IFRS
number uh which is also quite useful. So
if we can also get some some indication
around that. So so Gopal will give the
indication. My my only point is you know
just to put things in perspective uh
there is an economic value and there's
an accounting value. All these nuance
changes are
eventually on the accounting part of it.
There is obviously an implication in
terms of how positively IFRS can help us
but we as an organization would 100%
commit our on the economic value. Gopal
if you can just talk about this I
thinken we have actually kind of spoken
this even in past calls so therefore I
think our stance would still be the same
as in to say that uh I think we will
continue to evaluate businesses more on
an economic basis because end of the day
that's what will eventually translate in
terms of what is the outcome that we are
writing from a risk perspective
um transitions to IFRS obviously are
accounting changes which we obviously we
will be uh in that sense well prepared
and at this point of time obviously We
are getting most of our work done
internally whether it is in terms of
understanding the impact of change
getting systems geared up so that as and
when there is a clear regulatory
stipulations is what we have currently
indicated. So we will be kind of pretty
much ready with whatever it takes to do
the transition. But at the same time I
think what I I think we have been
speaking about also is the fact that as
and when we will eventually transition
to IFRS there will be a lot of in that
sense assumptions uh which will have to
be made by market at large. I think it
is important for again various
stakeholders to ensure consistency in
comparison a need for possibly to see if
we can get a lot more alignment with
some of those assumptions that the
market participants use. So I think our
endeavor is in that direction and which
is what we are working with the council
to see how we can possibly play that
role far better at this in the current
times. But obviously internally we are
pretty much well prepared. Major areas
of impact I think I've already called
out. So in that sense no specific
incremental areas to call out as a part
of the current uh impact assessment uh
that we have done but yes we are we are
ready and we will roll out whenever we
see the uh regulatory timelines coming
into action.
Okay. And then when we speak about
economic perspective we are talking more
about ROE and not combined ratio. Right.
This is the operator. Yeah. Because end
of the day I think whatever you write
has to kind of translate into a return
to stakeholders through a combination of
what we deliver on underwriting plus
obviously how effectively are we able to
put the cash flows to use. So hence to
that extent is what we will kind of be
largely driving as an institution.
Thank you sir. Thank you. That's it for
my side. Thanks Nidesh. Thanks Nesh.
Thank you.
Next question comes from the line of Ain
Singh with MK Global Financial Services
Limited. Please go ahead.
Yeah. Uh good evening. Thankful
opportunity. Just uh couple of
questions. First one is on uh you know
motor TP. Uh if I see again uh around
915 or close of reserve releases you had
this fiscal. Now of course still you
have not touched your FY23 onwards if I
see or Yeah. Now uh the backdrop is that
the price tech is not happening. uh do
you see I mean uh the support from
reserve releases to continue to provide
you know the support uh in terms of a
motorp claims ratio to to catch up with
you know the uh claims in place and then
on that front also another question
related is that okay industry has seen a
kind of a despite this coming the
overall non-cl expense going up now do
you see that scope next year if the
claims were to be under pressure opex
side because now the March 26 deadline
for EUM limits reaching some kind of a
you know uh sanity prevailing among the
some extreme or aggressive peers would
you would that lead to your opex further
improving from here because at the end
of the day that's a sort of a relative
market related phenomena you cannot
outpric yourself in the market if if the
peers were to improve will that also be
kind of a you know helpful and the
second one on the approve on renewal if
I read correctly India even in Asia
research capacities uh and pricing both
has been kind of a favorable. So in back
in that backdrop does that sort of a
help in terms of your profitability in
these kind of a very influence heavy
line item like commercialized. Thanks.
Okay. So maybe I will take the second
part first. I think what you observed is
absolutely right. Uh so so hence
obviously that aids us which is what we
have been kind of talking through. uh I
think the more the market gets sensible
in so far as the need for compliance to
the expense of management guidelines are
concerned that kind of definitely augers
well from an overall market discipline
standpoint. So and therefore and again
as you rightly indicated FI26 is a time
period that the regulator has stipulated
within which companies are expected to
tow the line when it comes to meeting
the guidelines on extens of management.
So, so obviously this is something that
uh we would be definitely kind of
closely watching for but at the same
time I'm sure all of you are also kind
of clearly hearing that even the
regulator is wanting to make sure that
as an industry pretty much everyone in
the market kind of follows the
discipline on compliance to extensive
management. So hence uh uh the short
answer is of course it augers well in so
far as uh favorable market development
is concerned and within that uh indeed
obviously that's something that we have
always seen when the market gets far
more sensible on underwriting then
ICumbard by virtue of its uh brand
technology service etc etc is obviously
able to kind of command an incremental
market growth uh without compromising on
underwriting outcomes. So, so that's the
response to the second one. To the
response on the third one, I think with
respect to the reinsurance uh renewal
cycle again, I think you all understand
insurance as much as what we do. Uh so
therefore uh so therefore in that sense
uh uh the the renewals are always
through cycles. You will always see
periods of softness and at some points
of time the market starts to get
hardened. Uh I think the key is end of
the day I think if you look at from our
standpoint what we have again
particularly in the commercial lines
where you relatively see higher
proportion of reinsurance we have
continued to stay disciplined on picking
risks which we think are viable from an
from a underwriting perspective uh
depend irrespective of which cycle the
market is currently operating at in
terms of uh the reinsurance renewals.
Now that's what is finding favor if you
were to see which is what put out also
on our investor presentation as in to
say that the quality of the partners
with whom we work clearly is kind of
pretty much there. So obviously we don't
in that sense want to take any
unnecessary credit risk. So we are very
very conscious of making sure that we
work with highquality panel of
reinsurers. So that gives us a lot of
comfort when it comes to getting
capacity and also now to your point on
terms obviously it's again we get start
we get terms which are better than the
market. uh so even this year at least
what we understand relative to the
market I think we have been given the
underwriting performance that we have
exhibited to the reinsurers I think we
believe we have been able to get terms
both on commissions and the cost that we
incur for protecting our net uh to be
possibly better than where the market is
placed at and that will again kind of
aid us in our ability to further uh
dwell on incremental market share so
that's in response to the third question
on reinsurance renewal cycle
Your first point on motor third party. I
think again I I keep saying this u I
think the ranges is what we have spoken
about in terms of the motor loss ratio.
Again I will keep saying we have to look
at motor as in the aggregate and the
range that we have spoken about even in
the earlier earnings call uh for the
segment has been between 65 to 67.
Broadly if you look at the loss ratio
outcome that has played out for even the
current year is pretty much within the
range that we have been kind of talking
about. So hence that's how we look at
now what can happen in case if no third
party price increase sustains for one
more year in FI26 obviously that means
we have to do a lot more work to make
sure that we are able to identify better
risk selection and continue to see how
we can drive profitable growth that's
what we will focus on and more
importantly let's say for the market
they will have to work much more harder
particularly for those companies which
have combined with no third party price
increase and a compliance to expense of
management ment yes is something that
some of those market participants will
have to work on. So again we believe
again favorably placed in terms of the
opportunity that one sees on uh motor
third party and finally on the point on
reserving I think again our approach to
the acturial principles pretty much
stands intact there is absolutely no
change in the way how we have been kind
of reserving for the portfolio in terms
of consistency and that's the reason
even if you would have seen the reserve
redundancy that you would have seen
across key lines we continue to see one
more year of reserve redundancy. So that
reflects the quality of reserving that
we have been able to kind of play up to.
So hence no change in the actial thought
process.
Thank you. Very clear. Thanks.
Thank you. Next question comes from the
line of Shria Shivani with CLSA. Please
go ahead. Hi, thank you for the
opportunity. I have one question that is
on the expense ratio for the quarter. Um
so the way I understood uh the the
impact of the 1 byN accounting last time
uh the quarters are similar in terms of
what happened in 3Q to 4Q in terms of
the volume growth that you got or uh how
much you have retained then ideally your
expense ratio should have been similar
to what it was in 3Q even the absolute
amount has declined in 4Q uh if I if I
don't talk about the ratio even the
absolute amount has declined. So what
has helped us in having much lesser net
commissions at least if if you can help
me understand this is just about the
quarter
yeah again it's like it's like the
question that keeps coming to us in
terms of the third party loss experience
on how the loss ratio movement are
happening between quarters uh I think
again I will kind of keep reiterating I
think our our focus is very clearly is
to make sure that expense plus
commissions put together as a company we
are very very conscious of making sure
that we run the overall operations at a
EOM threshold which is less than 30% and
which is what if you see on a full year
basis I think for us the expense of
management number stands at about
29.5%. Uh so hence I think we are pretty
much committed within a quarter various
factors in terms of business mix in
terms of efficiencies that we always
keep looking for in terms of our own
internal
processes and so there are numerous
factors that go into it. So hence which
is why we keep urging to keep looking at
numbers more on an annual basis rather
than a particular quarter and more so on
an absolute basis I think again there
can be many factors to it. So for
example I mean whenever if there are
periods where I do a lot more of those
investments in that quarter you will see
the cost hitting us uh and and so on. So
a better number to look at will be more
the expense of management number than
anything else. No and also share I mean
since you're and you're comparing
quarter three and quarter four just to
highlight right it's the configuration
of business that comes in in quarter
three we have far more new book that
comes in it's a season where you know
the sale of new goes sharing motor also
grows in a very very significant way in
January typical Jan first also is a
reasonably big line on the commercial
side of the business which can further
impact the expense ratio in a positive
manner so it's more driven by
configuration what nature of business
you write which creates their
differentiation then that's what and you
know that when these things happen and
you have a quarter where there's a new
coming in it would impact uh us uh in a
far more you know uh yeah okay yeah the
only thing I was getting confused that
if the retention ratios are similar
between 3Q and 4Q then your commission
rates should have been similar ideally
your net commission uh ratios but I get
the that if you've written more
commercial line in 4Q then obviously
yeah fair okay thank you thank you
thank you next question comes from the
line of Prahar Sharma Jeff please go
ahead
hi good evening uh just wanted to
develop upon a sweet comment on you know
the uh pricing stance by some of the
PSUs or broader market in the uh motor
vehicle business. Uh could you just
elaborate on this that uh you know from
what segments of uh general uh GI
operators did you see some bit of an
aggressive stance uh and uh has there
been any change because you know while
we talk about the EOM uh sunset for FI26
uh are the private ones also genuinely
trying to consolidate on pricing and
second connected to this is uh is there
a possibility or is there a discussion
around the EOM getting pushed out by a
year or so just so that everybody makes
it without too much disruption. Thank
you. So per I think uh on the PSU
aggression uh it's primarily driven very
extensively on the motor side. Uh will
it sustain too early to comment? There
were shades of that visible in quarter
three but quarter four if you see they
have overall buckled the trend and they
have gained significant market share
also in the uh motor segment. Uh it
would be anybody's guess in terms of
what their plan is. Uh we are pretty
ready to face whatever be the you know
trajectory that they have and uh we'll
wait and see how it pans out. uh we
would continue to as I said in my uh you
know in my you know initial remarks that
we would continue to flock because these
things can happen at multi multiple
levels uh at with multiple players
sometimes it's private sector sometimes
it's public sector but we need to stick
to our trajectory of what we want to do
uh with respect to expense of management
uh deferment uh our understanding is
that uh what has got called was full and
final. Uh we do believe it will be it
will be good in long term for the
industry if there's a feminist on that
count. Uh we are no one to comment in
terms of whether a dispensation will be
given for another year. But if you ask a
person another year of dispensation will
make them continue with the practice as
it exists and will not change anything
because then they can ask another year
of dispensation. So uh that's where we
would be, you know,
uh that's where we will leave this part
of the conversation at least.
Perfect. Thank you so much. Yeah. Thank
you.
Thank you. Next question comes from the
line of Aditi Jooshi with JP Morgan.
Please go ahead.
Uh yeah. Uh thank you for taking my
question. Uh just a very simple one.
Sorry I could not uh go through the
presentation. With respect to the
investment income, was
it in the fourth quarter was lower on an
year-on-year basis. I just wanted to
understand is it majorly on account of
interest income or on account of lower
uh realized gains. Yeah, we put that as
a part of the opening script. So largely
it's because of uh I mean the nature of
how we kind of real the nature of how we
run the overall investment book. The
short answer is capital gains. Quarter
four last year capital gains was roughly
about 150 crores plus this year pretty
much our capital gains is as good as a
very very small number of roughly about
6 crores. So that's large that's the
reason why you see uh the overall uh
investment income for Q4 of this year to
be slightly lower than the Q4 of last
year. But having said that, I think what
has worked well again as I said, I think
the treasury team has done a great job
in trying to make sure that the
portfolio has got significantly kind of
balanced to make sure that we go long
and hence uh which is why again time and
again we have been giving the yield to
maturity numbers which used to be less
than 7% that number as we speak
currently stands at about 7.55%. So so
this is for for here to state and hence
uh at least for quarter four the short
answer is capital gains. Yeah and also
you know something which I must put
across what our treasury team has done
is even over quarter and quarter we have
increased the yield of the book from 7%
to
7.55 so which is a big one with a tenure
also which has gone to 5.34
uh overall it puts us well in terms of
the current scenario that exists on the
that exist on the you know interest rate
part and also quarter three it was more
of tactical call where our investment
team felt that it was much better to
book capital gains in that quarter
versus what would happen in quarter 4.
Uh in hindsight it did work out for us.
Okay, that's clear. Thank you. Thanks.
Thank you. Next question comes from the
line of
Nirjnal with UPS security. Please go
ahead. Yeah. Hi. Uh so uh my question is
regarding getting to essentially say how
think about the group you know what
we've discussed uh they're still giving
lot of uncertainties as you mentioned
and the playbook could be different than
what we right now you know think about
as sorry to stop you we're not able to
hear you you're not that audible uh is
it better now?
Yeah maybe if you can just repeat your
question n that will help.
So one question on the on the growth
side uh because given this online will
kind of normalize from October
uh how one thing about overall growth
and the preferred areas will remain
health and obviously motor uh there's
been lot of competitive intensity which
is you know increased especially from PS
what I understand so any comment on
overall growth we are targeting in fact
six that is one and second is a
bookkeeping question on
other income from the non-operating
reserves which seems to be very high. Uh
so anything on that
so maybe I'll take the first one. Uh I
think on the growth side n uh the good
part is I think if you look at some of
the actions which are being taken both
at both at various governments and even
our own insurance regulator I think the
efforts have been very very positive. I
think for example the recent budget did
see a lot of a lot of uh uh people kind
of getting a higher disposable income
which kind of augers well now all of
this will start to kind of play through
maybe over the subsequent uh quarters so
that's a very very positive action which
comes from the government equally I
think regulators are doing their part in
terms of trying to keep relatively the
interest rate of the environment at far
more acceptable levels and the very
recent rate cuts again kind of augers
well in so far as driving uh consumpt
retail consumption and in general
driving consumptions are concerned. So,
so there are clearly lot of positive
factors which should aid when it comes
to let's say growth because ours is a
direct reflection of what happens in so
far as economic activities are concerned
and some of these positive actions by
the government and regulators a very
very well coupled with this I think if
you look at le side for the next two
quarters in general I think we are very
very positively placed in terms of how
we see the opportunity play out and also
what we kind of responded to the earlier
question on how the initial corporate
renewal cycle has been I think that
looks again very very promising you know
that's something that has started off on
a positive note right from the beginning
of the year so hence even for the rest
of the year one should see that cycle
play through so overall I think we are
kind of positively looking at in terms
of how the market should kind of play
out and within that I think what we have
spoken is to try and see how we can
continue to deliver that outperformance
with the industry growth numbers is what
we will be kind of penciling in first
two quarters you are absolutely right uh
in NRA in terms of the impact of one by
end will obviously kind of play out so
maybe to that extent industry growth
could be a little subdued but on a full
year basis I think we are very very
optimistic
and any uh comment on the combined basis
guidance uh if we are changing or
arising uh giving any new guidance I
think we are see on the guidance part
we've given a complete perspective if
the industry continues to deteriorate
our own belief would be that uh we are
part of the same pond right so uh you
would see uh
overall challenges but in our scheme of
things if there is improvement status
quo you would see us probably uh
improving more importantly it's the roe
part of it which we would focus on and
see what kind of returns we are able to
generate and in that we've always is
maintain that we want to see at least a
16 to you know 20% kind of a range for
us as a company being given to
stakeholders.
Awesome. Uh management of the
bookkeeping of the other income of the
nonoperating results seems to be very
high. Is it something regrouping or uh
yeah nothing specific but it is it is
business as usual for us. They will all
be driven by whatever the regulatory
stipulations are. uh and uh no no
specific uh changes per se. Oh, thank
you.
Thank you ladies and gentlemen. Due to
time constraints, we have reached the
end of question and answer session. I
would now like to hand the conference
over to Mr. Sanjie Mantri for closing
comments.
I think uh great to connect with all of
you. Uh closure of uh another financial
year and uh some exciting times ahead.
look forward to interacting with each
one of you uh as and when your time
permits. Uh we do believe that general
insurance industry is poised for a
decent year uh going forward and we will
keep in touch and keep you updated.
Thank you so much for joining in and all
the best to each one of you. Thank you
so much.
Thank you on behalf of ICL Lombard
General Insurance Company Limited. That
concludes this conference. Thank you for
joining us. You may now disconnect your
links.